If you don't do it nothing is possible. If you try to do it at least you have the hope. You
had that third failure in a row did you think I need [to] pack this in better?
Why not? I don't ever give up. I mean I'd have to be dead or completely incapacitated. So
many things go wrong when you're starting a company and often I think people ask you know, what mistakes
should you avoid making. And
you know my answer the question is don't even bother trying to avoid mistakes because you're going to make tons of mistakes right. And
the the important thing is actually learning quickly from whatever mistakes you make and not giving up.
Right and I mean there are things every single year of Facebook's existence that could have killed us are made it so that.
It just seemed like moving forward and making a lot of progress just seemed intractable
but you just kind of bounce back and you learn. And
nothing is impossible. You just have to kind of keep running through the walls.
It's hard changing your life.
It was hard when just over three years ago and the penobscot building in Detroit, Michigan. Where
I was operating my business, and I fell on some hard times, and I was sleeping in my office.
It was hard coming into the lobby and the security said: Excuse me, Mr.
Brown, can we see you for a moment? And I said yes, and I walked up to the counter
and he gave me an envelope. And
he said: Would you mind reading it here" and I opened the envelope and the envelope was from management that says this is
an office tower
it's not a hotel.
Please.
Do not sleep in your office.
And I said excuse me, sir. I said, I just worked long hours in
creating my business. I'm an entrepreneur. And
right now things are bad for me, but they're not going to be this way always.
and
I just asked for the opportunity to continue to operate like I'm doing. I'm not trying to make this my home and
it was hard coming through the lobby and
sometimes they would laugh. There's a guy talking about becoming successful and look at him
he's bathing in the bathroom upstairs on the 21st floor he sleeps on the floor.
him into other dreamers up there, look at him!
It was hard, ladies and gentleman coming to speak to people. And
I was facing financial difficulties in my own life.
I was behind on my bills and my dreams and I'm saying to them you can live your dream.
It was hardly ladies and gentlemen, it was very difficult to pick myself up each day believing.
But I can do it there was times that I doubted myself. I think God, why,  why is it happening to me?
I'm just trying to take care of my children and my mother. I'm not trying to steal a rod from anybody. I
just have to happen to me.
It was very hard.
Here's what I want to say to you.
For those of you that have experienced some hardships.
Don't give up on your dream.
No, one could have convinced me by holding off.
By continuing to push forward, by continuing to run toward my dream.
And one day I
would have my own talk show.
It's a long shot, ladies and gentlemen from liberty fitted an abandoned building auto flow.
Now we're knowing my mother father.
It's a long shot being here with you today in this goal in Atlantic the long shot.
No, college training labeled, educable mentally retarded, but I kept running toward my dream.
You tried to get into three colleges.
Each time they rejected.  You know I tried there's a
examination that young people if you want to go university of the taste take the examinations.
So I threw three times a lot of food. I feel for funny things that I fooled, a key,
primary school tests for two times and I failed
like a three times for the Middle school, middle schools. And
You would never believe in, in Jansel, my city there is only one Middle school.
That lasts only one year, it was changed from primary school, Middle school because our graduates of ours our, our school.
No, universe, you know middle school except us because we were too bad.
What effect did it have the
being rejected?
Well, I think we have to get used to it. We're not that good even today.
We still have a lot of people reject us. I think God
when I in the
graduate from Universities and before you know for three years.
I tried so in the university to apply jobs, or 30 times got rejected.
I went for a police if you know you're not good. I went to look even the
KFC. When KFC came to check a blog they
see
24 people went for the job.
23 people accepted I was only a guy. And
we went for please five people all of them accepted.
I was the only guy that I receive it. So for me being turned down, rejected out by the way
I told you that I was I apply for Harvard for ten times rejected.
Nothing works the first time when you try something new it probably won't work.
When you try something new several times it probably won't work and the turning point in my life came when I would hear good ideas
and I was so eager to be successful in selling. I would run out and try the ideas and they wouldn't work. I try a
way of getting an appointment or answering an objection or closing a sale it wouldn't work. And my natural response ah and
I think yes to be disappointed and then I realized nothing works at least the first few times.
So I decided I would try a new idea five or ten times before I pass judgment on. I would not just try it once
and quit like most people do and that changed my whole life.
It was a turning point of my life because I realized from then on if you've got a good idea.
And you've got a good goal, and you want to double your income and improve the quality of your life.
And you have to try new things in order to get new results.
It's not going to work the first time to say well that didn't work try something else and try something else and try something else.
Now if you try only two things can happen, what are they?
Succeed or fail. If you succeed you do more of it if you fail
you learn from it. Get smarter and try it again. So you cannot lose by taking action you can only lose by not taking actions.
Practice faithful persisting means never ever ever give up.
Chicken soup for the soul was rejected by a hundred and forty four publishers.
144 Publisher said we don't want to publish a collection short story. The title stupid chicken soup for the soul.
What does that mean people don't buy?
Collections of short stories, there's never been you know successful
chain of doing that. So literally we spent 14 months,
trying to find a publisher and we go to New York with our agent eventually our agent gave us the book.
And said I can't sell it. So we went to the national booksellers association convention down in Anaheim.
We went from booth to booth to booth for three days, and there were 4,000 publishers represented there there we go.
Would you publish a book? Would you publish a book? Would you publish your book? And we got no no no no no. It was
late on the third day that a little publisher from Florida after we'd gotten over 144 rejections said we'll read it. And
then they said we said well, how many copies do you think we'll sell? After they said yeah?
We'll buy it a couple weeks later. So we'll publish it and we said well. Maybe 20,000 if we're lucky.
And we said with our goals to sell a million and a half in a year now.
Now have you ever told someone your dream and had them laugh out loud at you.
He laughed out loud.
Now if we had given up after a hundred publishers had said no, I wouldn't be standing here today.
You know wouldn't it happen and so you've got to be willing to persevere.
Because we didn't take no. See when the world says no you say next. Let's practice that if I say no, you say: Yes!
Absolutely, there's only five or six billion people out there you can go and ask.There's over 4,000 publishers just here in the state of
California. So what we have is endless possibility, but you have to persevere.
It's as if the universe tests our commitment and so today we have
147 titles in Print we sold over 115 million copies.
We're in 47 languages and over a billion dollars where the chickens lose control if you've been sober a life.
So if you're willing to decide what you want believe, it's possible.
Consciously envision the future.
Feel the feelings of what it would feel like if you'd achieve this goal.
You can have anything and then you take action both obvious actions and inspired actions you can do anything.
There's no such thing as failure.
Failure is an idea because success is also a stupid idea.
Success and failure is not in the volumes of money flowing into your life.
Success and failure is not dependent upon the recognition that you're finding in the world.
You're successful with life if you know how to walk with joy, to help.
The first and foremost, success is
that you are not a slave to anybody's idea.
Don't become a slave to somebody's idea.
At least have your own idea.
Every idea, every part, every emotion ,every value that you have
is picked up from somewhere  and it rules you from within.
It rules you from within.
Your religion, your society, your
culture has trained you to believe. That this is it.